hey guys I thought this was a fun one
we're given two squares and two
triangles and it says find the area of
the red triangle I'll give you a hint
right now the method that I use to use
these notes right here we have the area
of any triangle is equal to 1/2 * one
side time another side time the sign of
the angle in between them and we also
have 306090 triangles where the
hypotenuse is twice as long as the
shortest side and the middle side is <
tk3 times the shortest side if you want
to try this on your own pause it right
now so I'm going to solve it in three 2
1 for this square up here we know all
the sides are congruent so they're all
equal to three and now looking at this
right triangle I'm noticing that the
medium side is < tk3 * the shortest side
that means it's going to be a 306090
triangle and we can align the
orientation just like this so we have
the shortest side here and the medium
side here which means this angle here
will be the 60° angle and this side is
twice as long as the shortest side so
it'll be equal to six and now looking at
this lower Square all the sides are
congruent so this last side will also be
equal to six another property of squares
all of these angles are right angles so
we can call this 90° here and in this
Square this would be 90° and let's call
this missing angle Theta now if we look
here 90 + 60 + 90 + Theta must equal
360° 90 + 60 + 90 is equal to 240 so 240
+ Theta = 360 after we subtract 240 from
both sides we get Theta equal to 120 so
we can update this up here to 120° and
now let's focus on this we're trying to
find the area of this red triangle we're
going to use these notes where the area
is equal to/ 12 * one side time another
side time the sign of the angle in
between them so our first side is going
to be three the other side is going to
be six and the angle between these two
sides is equal to 120° 6 * 3 is 18 and
half of that is 9 and the S of 120° is <
tk3 over2 so we end up with an area of 9
< tk3 over2 square units and that's
approximately equal to 7.79 square units
let's bring back all the other stuff and
we successfully found the area of the
red triangle let's put a box around it
how exciting